Akash Kumar Sahoo

B.Tech, Computer Science Engineering, 2021

Competitive Programmer with 3+ years of experience in Data Structures and Algorithms. Ability to leverage full-stack knowledge and experience to build interactive and user-centered website to scale. Actively looking for Full Time Software Development Engineer Role.



akashnikz@gmail.com 🔀

+91-7299456223

Chennai, India

linkedin.com/in/akash-kumar-sahoo-8b5348188 in

github.com/akashfit2max 👩

EDUCATION

B.Tech

SRM Institute of Science and Technology

2017 - 2021

Courses

 Computer Science Engineering

Class 12 - CBSE

Kendriya Vidyalaya AFS Tambaram

2016 - 2017

84.6%

91.38%

Courses

- PCM + Computer Science

Class 10 - CBSE

Kendriya Vidyalaya AFS Tambaram

2015 - 2016 9.6 cgpa

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineer Intern at Cognizant

Cognizant technology solutions

01/2021 - 06/2021

Tasks

- Hands-on experience on Web application development with MVC Architectural pattern.
- Hands-on experience in developing Microservice on Amazon Web Services Cloud.
- Experience in developing Microservice & REST End Points based on business requirements and functional specifications using Java Spring, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Maven, RESTful Web Services, Feign client, Lombok, H2 In-memory Database and Swagger.
- Work with senior developer to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.

Infra cloud automation Intern Capgemini

06/2019 - 07/2019

Tasks

- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Truyum Website

 Created a full stack website using java spring boot with Data JPA hibernate including spring security

Portfolio Website

 Fully Responsive modern website using Html, CSS and JavaScript, build with an amazing water ripples effect and a headline animation.

Realtime Chat App

Realtime chat app using socket.io and JavaScript

CERTIFICATES

Azure Administrator

Microsoft certified "Azure Administrator" (AZ-104).

SQL

Completed "SQL" certification from UDEMY.

Programming with C and C++

Completed "Programming with C and C++" certification from INTERNSHALA.

Introduction to html5

Completed "Introduction to html5" certification from COURSERA.

Git

Completed "Git" certification from PROGATE.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Geeks for Geeks Institutional rank 10. Solved 350+ problems in Leetcode

Participated in Math's Exhibition in SRM IST Chennai.

Won gold medal in "tug of war" in COMBUSTED'17 held at SRM IST,Chennai.

KVS CHENNAI REGION National Athlete

Volunteer of TEXUS (National level techno management fest).